Fine. I'll move it myself.
算了，我自己来吧
That suit…
这套战斗服是…
MONSTER SWEEPER INC.
（怪兽清扫有限公司）
Who are you?
你到底是谁？
I'm applicant number 2016.
准考证号码2016号
Kikoru Shinomiya. My hobby is killing kaiju.
四之宫琪歌露，兴趣是杀怪兽
Remember my name, all right?
给我记好了
Shinomiya!
四之宫
Hey, old man. You smell like kaiju.
大叔，你好像…有股怪兽的臭味？
Our work is cleaning up neutralized kaiju.
因为我们是做怪兽处理工作的
Why are cleaners like you at a place like this?
为什么处理业者会在这里啊？
All right, then.
嘿咻
Does he have a private suit, too?
难道那家伙也穿了私人战斗服？
Applicant number 2032.
准考证号码2032
I'm Kafka Hibino. Don't forget my name, little girl!
我叫日比野卡夫卡 给我记好了，小姑娘
They took our parking spot while I was talking!
不知不觉停车位被占走了！
That's one capable butler!
这管家真能干啊！
I just came here to participate in the rite of passage,
本来以为只是来走个过场
but it looks like I could enjoy my time here.
这不是有点意思吗？
I can't wait to beat you, Kafka Hibino.
我会让你哭着求饶的，日比野卡夫卡
-Let's go, Sebasu. -Yes, my lady.
-走了，濑羽须 -遵命
You already used your powers.
你马上就用力量了啊
Hey, you know, I just transformed the parts where you can't see.
但是你看，我只让 其他人看不到的地方变身
-That's not the problem here! -Hey there!
-不是那个问题吧？ -喂！
We heard a loud noise. Is there trouble here?
我们听到很大的声音 出什么问题了吗？
No, it's nothing. We're all right.
没有，什么事都没有
-Go inside quickly then! -Understood!
-那就快进去吧 -知道了
If you use your powers again, I'll send you back.
再用一次就把你强制遣返
Okay.
好啦
I gave up once,
虽然我一度放弃了
but this is my last chance to stand next to her!
但这是和她站在一起的最后机会
I'll never…
这次…
give up this time!
我绝对不会再放弃
Shit. What's going on?
奇怪，这是什么情况？
I can't keep up at all.
完全跟不上
I still keep up with my training from old habits,
明明我也保持着锻炼的习惯
and I work at my physically demanding job every day.
每天还做着重劳动的工作
The secondary exam has a physical fitness test and an aptitude test.
第二次测验分为 体力审查和资质审查两部分
Yes. The aptitude test looks at our natural qualities. We can't control that.
没错，资质审查是 我们无能为力的素质面
-That means… -Yeah.
-考虑到这部分… -嗯
We'll need to score high on the physical fitness test.
我们必须在体力审查取得高分
I was at least a little below average last time!
我之前好歹也是中下程度吧
So, why…
但是…
Is this what they mean when they say your body declines in your thirties?
这就是…过了30岁的体力衰退吗？
If I use my powers,
要是用力量的话
Could I outrun all of them in an instant?
是不是就能一口气超过所有人了呢？
Shit! My body is heavy.
可恶，身体好沉重
KAFKA HIBINO PHYSICAL FITNESS TEST RANKING
（日比野卡夫卡，体力审查结果）
219 OUT OF 225
（225人中排名219名）
KIKORU SHINOMIYA 5 OUT OF 225
（四之宫琪歌露 225人中排名第5名）
Wow, that was fast. I beat you already.
还真快啊，哭着求饶的样子
I'm Kafka Hibino. Don't forget my name, little girl… girl… girl!
我叫日比野卡夫卡 给我记好了，小姑娘…
Forget it!
快忘掉！
Forget my name right this instant!
快把我的名字忘掉！
I feel at ease. So, you really didn't use
我放心了，你真的没使用呢
your kaiju powers.
怪兽的力量
Everyone worked hard to get here.
大家都在努力
It would be unfair if I used my powers here.
只有我用那种力量，就太卑鄙了吧
Look, I'm trying to act all cool, but I should've used it!
可恶，我装什么帅啊？ 刚刚应该用的阿！
I'm so rusty!
都怪我的空窗期！
Your ranking might not just be because you're rusty.
前辈的排名会那么后面 可能不只是因为那样
Here are the applicants this year.
这是这次的考生
There are some interesting people.
有不少好像很有趣的家伙哦
You probably only care about beating kaiju, though.
不过你对打倒怪兽 以外的事也没兴趣吧？
Continue updating me. I'll listen as I work.
继续说，我边工作边听
Oh, wow, that's new.
哎呀，真难得
Let's see. I guess our star player would be…
那么，说到值得关注的人，首先是…
Haruichi Izumo.
出云阳一
Tokyo Neutralization University.
东京讨伐大学
Graduated at the top of class.
首席毕业
He's the top player out of this year's graduates.
他是今年毕业生中排名第一的潜力股
Another hopeful is Iharu Furuhashi.
然后是古桥伊春
Hachioji Neutralization Technical College, graduated at the top of the class.
是八王子讨伐专科学校 首席毕业的强者
IHARU FURUHASHI THIRD PLACE
（古桥伊春，体力审查第3名）
All right!
好耶！
The young hopeful of JGSDF,
陆上自卫队的明日之星
Aoi Kaguragi.
神乐木葵
AOI KAGURAGI FIRST PLACE
（神乐木葵，体力审查第1名）
He's a transfer applicant who declined a promised future at JGSDF
他放弃了在陆上自卫队的大好未来
in order to join the Defense Force.
申请加入防卫队
That's not all.
不仅是他们
I see more neutralization universities and technical college jackets than usual.
从各地讨伐大学和讨伐专科学校 来的学生比往年都还要多
These are elites who would usually go
他们本来就不想当现场小卒
for management positions rather than working on the field.
而是将目标放在储备干部的菁英
No wonder they're all so advanced.
怪不得大家程度都很高
And out of all of them, she's at the top.
然后其中最特别的存在，就是她
She was the youngest and top graduate
16岁就从加利福尼亚讨伐大学
of California Neutralization University at the age of 16.
跳级毕业的最年轻首席毕业生
She's considered to be the best talent in all of history.
被誉为史上第一天才的少女
She is Kikoru Shinomiya.
四之宫琪歌露
I'll crush her!
我要打倒她
How will my skills hold up to hers?
那么，要怎么对付她呢？
I'll be keeping an eye on her.
就让我见识看看吧
Everyone here is extremely talented, with Kikoru Shinomiya at the top.
以四之宫为首 具有丰富才能的成员齐聚一堂
-That's why you-- -So, she's--
-所以前辈才会… -那家伙…
Hello there. You finally realized how great I am?
哎呀，你终于发现我有多优秀了吗？
-Kafka Hibino-- -I didn't know you were that good!
-日比野卡夫… -原来你是这么厉害的家伙吗？
Don't lay a finger on our lady!
不准碰大小姐！
What's up with that old guy?
那个大叔在搞什么？
Maybe he's a fan of Shinomiya.
是在追四之宫吗？
That's the second time I saw you lose today, Kafka Hibino.
这是第二次哭着求饶呢 日比野卡夫卡
How many more times will I see that pathetic face of yours?
接下来还要让你哭好几次呢
I'll beat you for sure today!
我也会让你哭着求饶的！
Except that I'm already on the edge of being cut.
说是这么说，已经被逼到绝路了啊
We still have hope.
我们还有希望
For the upcoming aptitude test, in the past two years,
这两年在接下来的资质审查中
they've had applicants clean up kaiju remains.
有出过处理怪兽尸体的题目
What?
什么？
They assess your level of kaiju knowledge and teamwork
将对怪兽的知识和协调性列入考量
while raising awareness that neutralization isn't just defeating kaiju.
仅仅打倒并不能算是讨伐怪兽 似乎出现了这样的意识改革
This is why I decided to work in cleaning for my part-time job.
这也是我选择解体业打工的原因
All right!
好
-Let's hope the next one will go well! -Yeah!
-赌在下一轮吧 -哦！
NUMBER TWO
（第二）
So huge!
好壮观
I'm the head of the selection committee for the secondary exams
我是今年第二次测验的遴选委员
and the vice-captain of the Third Division, Hoshina.
第3部队的副队长，保科
The aptitude test will be held in this training area.
资质审查将在这个演习场进行
You all will be working with a kaiju in this training area.
你们要在这个演习场将怪兽…
Clean-up!
解体
You'll be neutralizing it.
…讨伐
-Neutra… -…lizing?
-讨… -伐？
I thought we're cleaning up here! Huh, Ichikawa-san?
不是说要解体吗？市川先生？
I'm talking about the previous two years! I'm disappointed too!
说到底那是前两年的事 我也很失望啊！
But we can't let you guys go in there empty-handed.
不过也不能就这样让你们空手上场
You'll be wearing these.
把这个穿上吧
This is by Izumo Tech.
这是出云科技制造的…
The G-X4552, huh?
G-X4552啊？
What is this?
这是什么？
Amazing.
好厉害
It's like the clothes are sticking to my body.
衣服好像吸住了身体一样
Physical evaluation and form assimilation complete.
身体测量与形状同化完成
Kaiju muscle fibers, fully operational.
怪兽肌肉纤维，运作正常
I can feel the suit merging with my body.
好像和身体合而为一
I can feel my muscles expanding. It's so hot.
能够感受到肌肉在膨胀，好热…
So, this is…
这就是…
These are the Defense Force's Kaiju Countermeasure Suits.
这是防卫队的怪兽对策战斗服
It's made from the biological tissue of kaiju
使用怪兽的生物组织制作
and greatly raises the fighting ability of the wearer.
能够大幅提升穿着者的战斗力
This is the best weapon to fight against kaiju for you guys that we have.
这是你们目前对抗怪兽最有效的装备
I'll be measuring the unleashed combat power for everyone who put on the suit.
开始对着装完毕的人员测量解放战力
Roger that!
了解
Reno Ichikawa.
市川雷诺
Unleashed combat power, 8%.
解放战力，8%
Haruichi Izumo, 18%.
出云阳一，18%
That's around what I expected.
差不多吧
-Aoi Kaguragi, 15%. -Yes, sir.
-神乐木葵，15% -知道了
-Iharu Furuhashi, 14%. -What?
-古桥伊春，14% -什么？
Unleashed combat power measures how much of the suit's power is being released.
解放战力是能发挥 多少战斗服力量的指标
If you've had a lot of training, you'd be around 20%.
经过训练后，通常会在20%左右
You'd usually be lucky if you see one applicant over 10%.
一年能出一个 超过10%的就很了不起了
We might really have the best pool of applicants in our history.
今年搞不好是 有史以来最丰收的一年啊
-Seriously? -The rumors are true.
-真的假的？ -跟谣传的一样
Kikoru Shinomiya.
四之宫琪歌露
Unleashed combat power is 46%!
解放战力…46%
Are you kidding me? She's already at Platoon Leader level!
开玩笑的吧？这可是小队长级别了
The best talent in history.
史上第一天才…
This might be the highest record for any applicant!
这是入队前的最高纪录吧？
I'm only at 8%.
我只有8%啊
Don't be so down, Ichikawa-kun.
别太沮丧，市川
Well, 8% is great for a first-timer.
第一次能有8%已经不错了
Honestly, as long as you're not at zero right now, you've passed.
老实说，现在只要不是零，都是合格
Though I've never seen anyone at zero in my time here!
不过我们也没见过零的家伙就是了
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Unleashed combat power, 0%!
解放战力，0%！
What's with that guy? We have our first zero!
那家伙是怎样？竟然出现零了
Maybe it's a measurement error.
奇怪，是测量错误吗？
Give me a bit more time!
再给我一些时间！
I'm pushing right now!
我正在努力！
Is he taking a shit? Pushing won't do anything!
你是要拉屎吗？努力也不会出来的
That old guy is hilarious! I like that dude.
那个大叔是怎样啊？ 超级有趣的，我很中意
He probably won't pass, though.
虽然应该是不合格了
Please focus on the selection process.
请你认真地审查
Why?
为什么？
Shit. I'm sure there's a trick to this.
可恶，应该有什么诀窍才对
I just have to figure it out before the exam ends.
必须在测验结束前找出来才行
Kafka Hibino, don't make me impatient.
真是令人着急呢，日比野卡夫卡
Show off the power you released in the parking lot!
快让我见识你在停车场的力量啊
The exam's about to end.
测验都要结束了
All right, everyone has their suits on?
这样一来，大家都穿上战斗服了吧？
Let's begin…
最终审查…
the final test.
开始吧
DEFENSE FORCE SELECTION EXAM FINAL ROUND
（防卫队员选拔测验，最终审查）
Here's what will happen in this test.
说明一下测验内容
The target is one honju that was placed in this large training area
目标是在广阔街道地形演习场配置的
designed like an urban district and 36 yoju.
主兽与36只余兽
We neutralized a kaiju that produced 16 victims in Hachioji last year
我们活捉了去年 在八王子造成16人遇难的怪兽
and captured it live to train our newcomers.
好用来培养新进队员
You'll be in combat using kaiju fighting weapons.
你们要以对怪兽用武器战斗
Each applicant will be monitored by being followed
每个人背后会有一台自动追踪无人机
by an automatic tracking drone.
来监视你们的行动
If we judge that your life is at risk,
如果我们判断有危及性命的情况
we'll release the suit shield remotely.
便会远端启动战斗服的护盾
But understand that this means you will be disqualified from that point.
但与此同时，也代表失去资格
Honestly, from this point forward, we can't guarantee that you'll survive.
说实话，在这之后 我们无法保证生命安全
Those who still have the will to continue…
即使如此，也有觉悟要继续的人…
proceed!
前进吧！
What the hell is that?
那是怎样啊？
Yoju 12 has been eviscerated.
消灭余兽12
Yoju 3 has been eviscerated.
消灭余兽03
Damn.
哦
-Wow. -Amazing.
-不错嘛 -好厉害
Dammit, we're going, too! Follow me, Ichikawa!
可恶，我们也上吧！ 好好跟着我，市川！
You're the one behind me!
那是我的台词吧！
These weapons are so heavy without any power from the suit.
没有战斗服辅助 这些装备真是超重的啊
-Only a zero percenter could understand-- -That's not a cool line!
-只有0%的我才能明白… -不要用耍帅的样子说啊！
But what should we do?
但是，该怎么办啊？
We don't have much attacking power.
我们没有那样的攻击能力
Oh, right, I forgot to mention.
啊，对了，我忘了说
We're joined by Captain Mina Ashiro for our aptitude test selection.
亚白米娜队长也会参加资质审查
Go ahead and show off what you've got!
各位鼓起精神好好表现吧
Let's bet on who becomes the coolest Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛谁能成为最帅气的队员吧
That's right. Who cares if I'm at zero?
是啊，就算是零又怎么样？
Calm down. This is my last and final chance.
冷静下来，这是最后的机会了
Ichikawa.
市川
Why did the judges assign a drone to follow each one of us?
审查方用无人机 跟着每个人的理由是什么？
You're right. If they only care about how many kaiju we neutralize,
的确，如果审查的标准只有讨伐数
they can just use a sensor to count the numbers.
那只要用感应器计算数量就好了
Right. They're looking at how we act based on our skills and situation.
没错，他们想看 我们会如何根据能力和状况行动
In that case, what we should do as someone with low attacking power is…
这样的话，攻击能力 较低的我们能采取的行动是…
Exactly.
没错
-We'll support the attackers! -Yes!
-尽可能支援攻击手！ -是！
Shit!
可恶！
Senpai! They're fighting to your right.
前辈！右方交战中
All right. Let's go around and support them.
好，绕过去进行支援！
The shape of that hoof…
那个蹄的形状…
I remember! This is the yoju we cleaned in collaboration with Iida Cleaners.
对了，这家伙是 和饭田解体一起处理的余兽
I see.
原来如此
That's why they added this to our collection of weapons.
所以装备中才配备了这样的东西
Take this!
吃我一记！
A stun grenade?
震撼弹？
This guy has developed hearing to make up for his deteriorating eyesight.
这家伙由于眼睛退化 所以听觉非常发达
So, we'll throw that off balance and find a target!
针对这点就胜券在握了！
-It's the belly! -Huh?
-腹部！ -什么？
The skin on his belly is thinner than the rest of his body.
那家伙腹部的皮肤比其他地方薄
-Aim for the belly! -What?
-瞄准腹部！ -什么？
Nice assist. Shinomiya fan!
好助攻，在追四之宫的大叔
I'm not her fan!
我没在追她！
-Nice job, Senpai! -Thanks.
-干得好，前辈 -谢啦
I haven't cleaned up all those kaiju for nothing.
我可是处理过无数的怪兽呢
I know all about you, inside and out!
这些家伙，我连内脏都能一眼看透！
I can do it without using my kaiju powers!
有机会，就算不用怪兽的力量也行
I'll compensate for all the mishaps up to this point!
至今为止的蠢样就让它一笔勾销
I'll throw the next one! Let's just keep going.
下次由我来投掷，就照这个样子…
Another kaiju?
另一头？
Senpai!
前辈！
Area Delta, number 2032 has been injured.
德尔塔区，编号2032受伤
Vitals are abnormal. He's unable to fight.
生命体征异常，无法战斗
Yoju 23 is continuing to attack!
余兽23仍继续追击
Prepare the remote shield.
准备启动远端护盾
Ouch…
好痛…
Shit. They're releasing the remote shield.
不妙，他们要启动远端护盾了
Understand that this means you will be disqualified.
也代表失去资格
Stand up. She's…
站起来，那家伙…
She's watching me.
那家伙在看着
I can't be acting more pathetic than I already am!
不能再让她看见丢脸的模样了
Releasing the Remote Shield!
远端护盾启动
So, he's the first one out, huh? Figures.
第一个淘汰的果然是他啊
He was a funny dude,
虽然是个有趣的男人
but it can't be helped.
但也没办法
That's your third losing face, Kafka Hibino.
这是你第三次哭着求饶了 日比野卡夫卡
I won't allow any victims where I'm fighting.
在我的战场上，不允许出现牺牲者
Kikoru! You saved me--
琪歌露，帮大忙…
I'll take care of this gracefully.
我会华丽地收拾它们的
You just lie there pathetically, okay?
你就在那里没用地打滚吧
-She's going for the main target! -That's mine!
-她要去狩猎主兽吗？ -别想抢在我前面
Don't be so distracted!
切忌东张西望
So powerful. Is it really the same weapon as mine?
那是什么威力啊？ 真的是同样的装备吗？
Unleashed combat power makes a huge difference in our attacking force.
解放战力的不同 威力竟然会差这么多吗？
I'm going too!
可恶，我也…
Senpai!
前辈！
It's broken? I can't stand up anymore.
骨折了吗？这样没办法站起来
Can you hear me, number 2032?
2032号，听得到吗？
It's Hoshina, from the operation room.
我是作战室的保科
Your vitals are abnormal.
你的生命体征有异常
Broken bones in various places.
恐怕有多处骨折
There may be damages to your internal organs.
不排除可能也有内脏损伤
No way.
怎么…这样？
I have to give up?
只能放弃了吗？
But if I still have a chance, I'll….
不，只要还有可能的话，我…
KAFKA HIBINO
（2032，日比野卡夫卡）
UNLEASHED COMBAT POWER: 0%
（解放战力：0%）
There's no way I could stand next to her.
想站在那家伙身边
There's no way.
已经不可能了
It's always the talented ones who pass.
被录取的总是有才华的人
As judges, we recommend that you retire.
作为审查方，我建议你弃权
The shield won't protect you from everything.
护盾也并非万无一失
I'm the only one that can decide
能决定要不要放弃的
whether to give up.
只有我自己
Senpai.
前辈
I'm at no age to have dreams.
一把年纪了，还在追逐梦想
I know it's lame.
我知道很不像样
But I decided to bet on my entire life so far
但我想赌上迄今为止的人生
to chase after this one thing.
再次拼一把
UNLEASHED COMBAT POWER: 0.01%
（解放战力：0.01%）
I'll never…
这次…
I'll never give up this time!
这次我绝不放弃！
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰